Kang Hsieh

M.Sc. Aerospace Engineer | Software Developer

• 60486 Frankfurt, Germany

™ kanghsieh1990@gmail.com

**** +49 176 96546054

in kanghsieh

kanghsieh



Combined experience and knowledge in both aerospace engineering and software development. Having over 6 years of successfully managed projects in technical operations of aerospace industry. Recent graduate of a software development coding bootcamp. Data-driven, structured and pragmatic approach to continuous improvement of operations.

SKILLS

Programming languages

Javascript, Ruby, Python

DevOps Tools

Git, Github, Heroku, Vercel

Frameworks

Next.js, React.js, Ruby on Rails

Other tools

Tableau, Matlab, MS Office, Slack

Backend

Node.js, SQL, Postgresql, MongoDB

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Freelance

- Building an MVP for an HR Management web application using Next.js framework
- Building a web application to connect refugees in need with volunteers for humanitarian aid using Next.js & MongoDB framework

Web Development Teaching Assistant

2022 - present

2022 - present

Le Wagon

• Teaching Ruby, Javascript, SQL, Ruby on Rails to coding bootcamp students

Project Manager & Revenue Analyst

2019 - 2021

Lufthansa

- Forecasted demand patterns on several intercontinental routes which accounted for 420 Mio. EUR of revenue.
- Optimized revenue performance by exploiting large cloud-based datasets of the airline's historical flight data of 10-20 years.
- Led a cross-functional agile project team of 10 people consisting of software developers, IT solution managers and commercial managers.
- Reached the goal of **deploying** a revenue management system **MVP into production** on time and below budget.
- Contributed to a **successful start of sale and operation** of an entire new airline only 1 year after project start.

Project Engineer

2016 - 2019

Lufthansa Technik

Accountable for lean production and digitalization, project management, business intelligence and data analysis and leading several projects:

- Improved the work processes efficiency of the structure maintenance team by 10%.
- **Developed digital performance monitoring** and implemented a new maintenance concept for aircraft cabin maintenance leading to an overall reduction of process times by 5%.
- Introduced state-of-the-art business intelligence, data mining and sourcing to tech ops performance monitoring using SQL and Tableau.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development, Software Engineering

2022 - 2022

Le Wagon

10 week full time intensive coding bootcamp Ruby on Rails, Javascript, SQL, HTML, CSS

Aerospace Engineering, Master of Science

2014 - 2016

RWTH Aachen University

Mechanical Engineering, Bachelor of Science

2009 - 2014

RWTH Aachen University

CERTIFICATES

Project Management Professional (PMP)

Tableau Analyst

S LANGUAGES

German

English

Chinese Mandarin